swoop.com 2017-07-04

# Swoop Privacy Policy

## Swoop Advertising Services Privacy Policy

Welcome. The information below explains how Swoop collects, uses, and discloses information as we provide services to users, publishers, brands, websites and others.

Swoop provides services to websites and consumers that help personalize and customize consumers’ user experience and provide more relevant content and offers for consumers as they browse our partners’ websites and the web. Our “Advertising Services” allows us to develop a deep understanding of the content on the page you are reading, and combine that with a deep understanding of the type of products and services that may be relevant to that content. When we discover an offer or deal that is highly relevant to this content we alert you to it and invite you to explore and learn more. If we don’t find something interesting, we won’t say anything at all.

We deliver Advertising Services to consumers on our partners’ websites and on other websites that may display advertising.

The information below is designed to help you understand how our Advertising Services collect and use data.

Swoop is not a company that sells information about consumers to other companies for their direct marketing purposes.

1\. We do not sell data we collect in any individualized form – period.  
2\. Swoop is in the business of helping publishers, brands and consumers find one another using the Swoop platform.

## Our Values

Swoop believes that when consumers are able to work with brands, websites and services that they trust, then consumers will be more willing to share information and engage with brands and websites. We want to create an environment where everyone wins and can feel comfortable with how information is collected and used.

We recommend that consumers review the privacy policies of the websites they visit and of the online service providers used, including those of their Internet service provider. Paying close attention to the privacy policies of the websites visited remains one of the best ways to make informed choices about privacy.

## What is Swoop?

Swoop is a service that helps publishers and brands build customized websites and services within their own pages and helps the publishers and brands connect directly with interested consumers. Our Advertising Services are embedded within our partners’ websites and help our partners to understand how consumers use those websites, what brought them to those pages and what information, content and offers might be of interest to consumers.

Swoop helps tailor content, including offers and other promotional information, to the consumer within websites using our Advertising Services. Additionally, Swoop’s Advertising Service may also help make available offers or advertisements on other websites around the web where interest-based advertising may be displayed.

## An Example of Notices through the Advertising Services

An example of when you might see our Advertising Services being used occurs when a recipe website customizes content in a clearly delineated area (a “widget”) to show information such as pricing or offers related to a particular recipe or ingredient in a recipe. Our Advertising Services also help identify new content relationships, create links to existing content and create entirely new pages with unique combinations of content intended to help improve the Advertising experience and make offers available in a more natural and useful way for consumers.

A sample example of the content customization provided by our Advertising Services is below and is represented as the green tags. Individual implementations of our Advertising Services may differ in appearance:

Our Advertising Services are designed to help consumers find offers and information that may be of interest to them and to help publishers and brands provide information consumers want. If a consumer clicks on particular content that has been created using our Advertising Services, the resulting user experience should better fit their interests because of our Advertising Services.

## INFORMATION SWOOP PROCESSES AND HOW IT IS USED

Personally Identifiable Information and How Swoop May Receive and Use It. Swoop does not generally collect or use any personally identifiable information about individual consumers through our Advertising Services. However, there are some circumstances where Swoop may get personally identifiable information. For example, if a consumer desires to receive a coupon through one of our offers Swoop may need to collect certain information in order to deliver that coupon or otherwise help the consumer receive the offer. Similarly, if a consumer requests a sample or wants to sign up to receive special offers, certain personally identifiable information may be needed to deliver these services. Swoop uses this information for its internal business purposes to provide the Advertising Services but does not otherwise share the information unless doing so is consistent with the purpose for which the information was provided.

## What Other Information Does Swoop Receive and How Do We Use It?

To help our Advertising Services provide better content and Advertising experiences to all consumers and to provide aggregate statistics about consumer use of our Advertising Services, we collect information about consumers’ use of our partners’ websites and the interaction with our Advertising Services implementations.

Website Usage and Analytics. We may collect non-personal information such as information about consumers’ browser and website navigation within our partners’ websites, including log file activity associated with this navigation and search queries that directed consumers to our partners’ website. When consumers visit websites, information identifying the website they arrive from and the next website they visit is generated and available to the website operator for analysis. Swoop uses such information on an aggregated basis alongside similar information to help Swoop improve and develop our products and improve user experience. This aggregated information may include basic reporting metrics like the number of consumers who discovered content through the Swoop-suggested content and connections, how frequently users return to a website, and other information available to the websites on which our Advertising Services are made available. Aggregated information will also be used to help Swoop and its partners optimize the Advertising Services. Such aggregate data does not contain personally identifiable information.

Cookies and Log Information. Cookies are files that web servers place on an Internet user’s computer that are designed to store basic information (such as visitor preferences). Cookie technology remains a fundamentally important part of how websites customize users’ online experiences. Through the use of cookies or similar technologies, we may store basic information about your visits to a partners’ website, in anonymized form, so that we can help improve consumers’ online experiences.

Swoop may receive a consumer’s IP address, pages or products browsed, technical attributes about the consumer’s browser request, browser type, browser language, search query, details about whether the consumer has made a purchase, and date and time information. We may receive this information or collect it jointly on the websites on which our Advertising Services are made available.

## Information Retention

Our business partners limit Swoop’s collection, use, and disclosure of information through our Advertising Services. We keep information we need to provide our services to our partners only so long as we have a valid business purpose.

## SWOOP TRANSFER AND INFORMATION SHARING

We do not share any individual level information we collect for any direct marketing purposes except in connection with responding to a consumer’s request. We may share aggregate information about the use of the Advertising Services with the businesses that use our services. This information does not identify any individual consumer. Swoop may otherwise share information it collects if doing so is appropriate to carry out a consumer’s request; or if Swoop believes that doing so is legally required; or it is in Swoop’s interest to protect its property or other legal rights; or the rights or property of others. In any case, as discussed above, where we do collect personally identifiable information we take steps to make clear that we are collecting such information and how it will be used. Information possessed by Swoop may be transferred in connection with any sale or disposition of the business as permitted by law or agreements with our partners.

## CHANGES AND UPDATES

We may occasionally update our policies and procedures relating to Swoop. When we do, we will also revise the “effective date” on these pages. The Swoop services are offered principally on behalf of and through other online businesses, such as website publishers and e-commerce providers. We encourage you to regularly review the privacy policies of pages you visit on the Internet.

## CONTACTING SWOOP

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about Swoop or Swoop and privacy, please email us at [privacy@Swoop.com](mailto:privacy@Swoop.com). In the event that we are still unable to resolve your concerns, Swoop is committed to cooperating to achieve a proper resolution of your privacy concerns.

Postal Mail Address:  
Swoop Inc.  
125 Cambridgepark Drive  
Cambridge, MA 02140

Effective Date: January 1, 2012
